Matthew Farquharson

UX/UI Designer

Portfolio: matthewfarquharson.design
Email: matthewfarquharson@gmail.com

Minneapolis, MN

Phone: 763-607-7210

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/matthewfarq



Summary

With a passion for user research and information architecture, I think that by studying and observing cognitive and behavioral patterns, one can design experiences with the ability to influence human behavior. If you're interested in working with someone who values the importance of designing user-centered products while improving the ROI of a company, please reach out. I'd love to talk with you.

Projects

Ballistic | May 2020

Lead UX / UI Designer

Ballistic is a mobile marketplace app designed for the modern gamer. Aside from purchasing games, users can customize their preferences and stay up to date with the latest news in the game industry.

Kudu | March 2020

Lead UX / UI Designer

Designed for both desktop and mobile devices, Kudu is a social media management platform that empowers digital content creators to manage, share, and track the activity of their digital assets.

Experience

Thinkful Apprenticeship | Product Design Flex | October 2019 - June 2020

- Learned industry best practices and design process standards with a focus on UX research, visual design, and front-end development.
- Created and deployed projects while learning new tools and frameworks by collaborating one-on-one several hours a week with a lead UX/UI designer at AWS.

Quinn Violins & Fret Central | Sales Representative | May 2018 - Present

- Created and managed all online product listings on third-party marketplace sites.
- By familiarizing myself with common customer questions, I made it my goal to design user-centered product listings with all the necessary specs and images to enabled customers to make online purchases without any assistance.
- After doing this, the music shop experienced a 500% increase in online sales and had the most profitable quarter of their 20+ years of business.

Education

University of Colorado, Boulder Bachelor of Music, Violin Performance GPA: 3.6 | 2013 – 2018

Skills

User Research User Flows
Wireframing Mockups
Prototyping Usability Te

Prototyping Usability Testing
Figma Sketch

InVision HTML/CSS